BARRETT FLEMONS

Interaction Designer | Front End Developer

About

An Interaction Designer who lives for the challenge, constantly strives to learn and experience more.

The charismatic connection needed to bring teams further. I happen to love getting my hands dirty in code when not designing interfaces and experiences.

The charismatic connection needed to bring teams further. I happen to love getting my hands dirty in code when not designing interfaces and experiences.

Skills

Methodology	Programs
Design Thinking	 Illustrator
• Wireframing	 Photoshop
 Usability Testing 	 InDesign
Rapid Prototyping	 After Effects
· 3D Modeling	• Premiere Pro
Information Architecture	• Adobe XD
• Front-End Development	• Rhino 3D
Creative Problem Solving	· Cinema 4D

Contact

barrettflemons@gmail.com

289.828.0726

Toronto, On, Can

Experience

bflemons.com

Web Designer, Co-op · Canadian Tire

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Collaborated within a small team in revitalizing and maintaining Canadian Tire's e-learning platform. Executed overhaul of admin site and guided development of admin and user facing FAQ pages, reducing customer service tickets. Produced proprietary digital and print materials resulting in increased user engagement.

Web Designer, Contract • Canadian Tire

Nov 2017 - Jan 2018

Independently executed design and development of a digitized version of a administrator user guide. Headed up direct changes to the visual design based on feedback of the users, and built a template for a future French version.

Freelance Designer

Jan 2016 - Present

Produced illustrations and UI designs based on individual clients needs.

Education

Bachelor of Interaction Design

Sept 2014 - Apr 2018

+ Certificate in Creativity and Creative Problem Solving Sheridan College Institute of Technology & Advanced Learning Oakville, Ontario

Projects

May 2017 - July 2018

CTU Admin Site Redesign · Canadian Tire

Investigated client pain points on admin-facing internal employee training website. Spearheaded structural and visual redesign and front-end development, resulting in drastically reduced active customer service tickets.

Sept 2016 - May 2017

Data Visualization • Innovation Hub

Investigated the Canadian housing crisis and factors that impact home ownership. Launched an illustrated and coded web visualization to demonstrate the crisis, with a call-to-action for Canadians to start saving early.

Nov 2017 - Jan 2018

CTU Admin Guide Digitization • Canadian Tire

Amalgamated user feedback on current print guide into tangible design requirements. Designed layout and developed the guide as a web-based solution resulting in a reduction in QA calls.

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

Usability Testing • KPDI

Evaluated client website following Nielson Heuristic principles. Devised testing plan for key problem areas and conducted several user tests. Proposed solutions to client pain points based on findings. Recommendations were enacted by KPDI.